Guide to the Vassar College Board of Trustees Records, 1861-2014
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- SERIES II. TRUSTEE COMMITTEES, 1861-2011
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee — Vassar College Art Department and Gallery, architectural plans, 1989 Oct 19; (13 boards) [RESTRICTED] (Box 50)
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee — Vassar College Art Department and Gallery, architectural plans, 1989 Oct 19; (7 boards) [RESTRICTED] (Box 53)
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee — "Vassar College Athletics Fields" by Leo A Daly, design plans, 2002 Apr; [RESTRICTED] (Box 54)
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee — Vassar College Drama and Film Center, architectural plans, 2000; (14 boards) [RESTRICTED] (Box 51)
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee — Vassar College Drama and Film Center by Cesar Pelli & Associates, concept art, 2000; [RESTRICTED] (Box 53)
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee — "Vassar College Getty Foundation Heritage Grant - Historic Preservation Manual," Platt Byard Dovell White Architects LLP, 2007 Jun 15; [RESTRICTED] (Box 54)
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee — "Vassar College Landscape Master Plan" by Sasaki Associates, Inc., 1992 Oct; [RESTRICTED] (Folder 52.5)
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee — "Vassar College Landscape Master Plan, Final Report", 1988 Sep 1; [RESTRICTED] (Folder 52.6)
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee — Vassar College Libraries renovation, floor plans, undated; (7 leaves) [RESTRICTED] (Box 53)
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee — "Wimpfheimer Nursery School - Draft Building Evaluation Report", 2005 Aug; [RESTRICTED] (Box 54)
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee — Unidentified interior concept art, undated; [RESTRICTED] (Folder 52.7)
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee — Unidentified photograph of indoor basketball courts, undated; [RESTRICTED] (Folder 52.8)
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee AND Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1861-1862 (Box 47)
  - Coeducation, Committee on, 1973-1975 (Folder 30.10)
  - Education of Women at Vassar, Committee on, 1971 (Folder 30.11)
  - Endowment Committee, 1952-1957 (Folders 30.12-30.13)
  - Faculty and Studies Committee, 1915-1938; [RESTRICTED] (Folders 30.14-30.17)
  - Faculty and Studies Committee, 1938-1971; [RESTRICTED] (Folders 31.1-31.9)
  - Investments and Finance Committee, 1964-1984; [RESTRICTED] (Folders 31.10-31.16)
  - Investments and Finance Committee, 1985-1989; [RESTRICTED] (Folders 32.1-32.9)
  - Investments Committee, 1989 Mar - 1991 May; [RESTRICTED] (Folders 32.10-32.17)
  - Investments Committee, 1991 May - 1993 Dec; [RESTRICTED] (Folders 33.1-33.17)
  - Investments Committee, 1994 Mar - 1998 Jun; [RESTRICTED] (Folders 34.1-34.16)
  - Investments Committee, 1998 Sep - 2002 May; [RESTRICTED] (Folders 35.1-35.6)
  - Investments Committee, 1999 Sep - 2000 Feb; (4 folders) [RESTRICTED] (Box 56)
  - Investments Committee, 2000 May -2001 Mar; (3 folders) [RESTRICTED] (Box 57)
  - Investor Responsibility Committee, 1991-2002; [RESTRICTED] (Folder 35.7)
  - Investor Responsibility Committee, 1991 Oct - 2004 May; [RESTRICTED] (Box 57)
  - Joint Committee with the Faculty, 1957-1960 (Folder 36.42)
  - Nominate a President (Alan Simpson), Committee to, 1964-1965 (Folder 35.8)
  - Nominations Committee, 1984 Dec (Folder 35.9)
- SERIES III. SECRETARY'S FILES, 1937-2005
  - Set 1 - Subject Files, 1937-1951
    - Advisory System, 1943 (Folder 35.10)
    - Agendas for Board of Trustee Meetings, 1942-1950 (Folder 35.11)
    - Alumnae Committee of Seven Colleges, 1937-1943 (Folder 35.12)
    - Alumnae House, 1938-1942 (Folder 35.13)
    - Budget Committee, 1943-1950 (Folder 35.14)
    - Buildings and Grounds, 1938-1951 (Folder 35.15)
    - Business Administration, Committee on, 1949-1950 (Folder 35.16)
    - By-Laws, 1939-1942 (Folder 35.17)
    - Calendar, 1944-1946 (Folder 35.18)
    - Chairman of the Board of Trustees, 1939-1947 (Folder 35.19)
    - Chaplaincy, 1938-1945 (Folder 35.20)
    - Comparative Expenditures, 1937-1941 (Folder 35.21)
    - Communications, 1937-1950 (Folder 35.22)
    - Comptroller, 1946-1951 (Folder 35.23)
    - Conferences with Faculty, 1942-1946 (Folder 35.24)
    - Cooperative Houses / Self-Help Houses, 1938-1939 (Folder 35.25)
    - Dinner Meetings, 1938-1946 (Folder 35.26)
    - Economies, 1946-1947 (Folder 35.27)
    - Endowment, 1938-1950 (Folder 35.28)
    - Euthenics, 1938-1942 (Folder 35.29)
    - Executive Committee Recommendations, 1937-1944 (Folder 35.30)
    - Faculty and Studies Committee, 1937-1951 (Folder 35.31)
    - Faculty Club Committee and Faculty Representation, 1939-1943 (Folder 35.32)
    - Faculty Representation on the Board of Trustees, 1942 (Folder 35.33)
    - Faculty Salaries and Benefits, 1943-1947 (Folder 35.34)
    - Former Trustees Still Leaving, undated (Folder 35.35)
    - General Manager, 1937-1951 (Folder 35.36)
    - Gifts, 1941-1945 (Folder 35.37)
    - Governance, 1943 (Folder 35.38)
    - Health, 1939-1941 (Folder 35.39)
    - Helen Kenyon Lectureship Fund, undated (Folder 35.40)
    - Housing, 1939-1946 (Folder 35.41)
    - Interior Decorator, 1938-1939 (Folder 35.42)
    - Investments and Finance, 1937-1951 (Folder 35.43)
    - Lisburne Grange, 1946 (Folder 35.44)
    - Maintenance Funds, 1938 (Folder 35.45)
    - Medical Examinations, 1939 (Folder 35.46)
    - Memorial Tablets, 1937, 1940 (Folder 35.47)
    - Mortgages, 1939 (Folder 35.48)
    - Nominations, Committee on, 1938-1949 (Folder 35.49)
    - President Blanding to the Board of Trustees, 1945-1951 (Folder 35.50)
    - President MacCracken, 1937-1946 (Folder 36.1)
    - Publications of Faculty, 1937-1942 (Folder 36.2)
    - Refugee Scholars, 1939 (Folder 36.3)
    - Resolutions, undated (Folder 36.4)
    - Scholarships, 1938-1947 (Folder 36.5)
    - Seven College Conference, 1942 (Folder 36.6)
    - Seventy-Fifth Anniversary, 1938-1940 (Folder 36.7)
    - Social Museum, undated (Folder 36.8)
    - Three Year Program, 1945-1946 (Folder 36.9)
    - Treasurer's Reports to the Board of Trustees, 1937 Jun - 1945 Oct (Folder 36.10)
    - Treasurer's Reports to the Board of Trustees, 1946 Feb - 1951 May (Folder 36.11)
    - Trustee Committee Lists, 1938-1947 (Folder 36.12)
    - Tuition, 1945 (Folder 36.13)
    - Undergraduate Life Committee, 1937-1951 (Folder 36.14)
    - Vassar Institute — War Time Community Service, 1942-1944 (Folder 36.15)
    - Veterans, 1942-1946 (Folder 36.16)
    - World Youth Conference, 1938-1939 (Folder 36.17)
    - Miscellaneous, 1940-1947 (Folder 36.18)
  - Set 2 - Subject Files, 1977-1989
    - Castle in Brissac, 1982-1985 (Folder 36.19)
    - Committees — Advisory Group on Coeducation, 1984; [RESTRICTED] (Folder 36.29)
    - Committees — Executive Committee, 1983-1985; [RESTRICTED] (Folders 36.30-36.31)
    - Committees — Governance Committee, 1982-1984; [RESTRICTED] (Folder 36.32)
    - Committees — Investments and Finance Committee, 1982-1986; [RESTRICTED] (Folder 36.33)
    - Committees — Investor Responsibility Committee, 1985; [RESTRICTED] (Folder 36.34)
    - Committees — Minority Affairs Committee, 1989; [RESTRICTED] (Folder 36.35)
    - Committees — Nominations Committee, 1977-1985 (Folder 36.36)
    - Committees — Personnel Committee, 1984; [RESTRICTED] (Folder 36.37)
    - Committees — President Search Committee, 1985 (Folder 36.38)
    - Committees — Committee on Religious Life, 1985-1986; [RESTRICTED] (Folder 36.39)
    - Committees — Student Conference Committee, 1984 (Folder 36.40)
    - Committees — Student Life Committee, 1984 (Folder 36.41)
    - Grants, 1985 (Folder 36.20)
    - Mailings to Trustees, 1982-1985 (Folder 36.21)
    - New York State Liquor License, 1983-1989; [RESTRICTED] (Folder 36.22)
    - Nursery School, 1983 (Folder 36.23)
    - Presidential Review, 1984-1985 (Folder 36.24)
    - Reports, 1986 May; [RESTRICTED] (Folder 36.25)
    - Sunrise Lane, 1983 (Folder 36.26)
    - Trustee Minutes — Access, 1984 (Folder 36.27)
    - Urban Center, 1983 (Folder 36.28)
  - Set 3 - Board of Trustees Minutes, 1980-2005
    - Board of Trustees and Executive Committee Minutes, 1980 Oct - 1982 Feb (Box 37)
    - Board of Trustees and Executive Committee Minutes, 1982 May - 1983 Dec (Box 38)
    - Board of Trustees and Executive Committee Minutes, 1983 Dec - 1985 Jan (Box 39)
    - Board of Trustees and Executive Committee Minutes, 1985 Feb - 1987 Aug; [RESTRICTED] (Box 40)
    - Board of Trustees and Executive Committee Minutes, 1988 Feb - 1991 Oct; [RESTRICTED] (Box 41)
    - Board of Trustees and Executive Committee Minutes, 1992 Feb - 1998 Feb; [RESTRICTED] (Box 42)
    - Board of Trustees and Executive Committee Minutes, 1998 May - 2005 May; [RESTRICTED] (Box 43)
- SERIES IV. MISCELLANEOUS, 1868-2006
  - Biographies of Trustees, circa 1987-1988; [RESTRICTED] (Folder 36.42)
  - Biographies of Trustees, 1993-1996; [RESTRICTED] (Folders 36.43-36.46)
  - Biographies of Trustees, 1999-2002; [RESTRICTED] (Folders 36.47-36.50)
  - Biographies of Trustees, 2004-2005; [RESTRICTED] (Folders 36.51-36.52)
  - Card file index to Minutes of the Full board, A-L, approximately 1930-1995; [RESTRICTED] (Box 44)
  - Card file index to Minutes of the Full board, M-Z, approximately 1930-1995; [RESTRICTED] (Box 45)
  - Card file index to Minutes of the Executive Committee, A-C, approximately 1930-1995; [RESTRICTED] (Box 45)
  - Card file index to Minutes of the Executive Committee, D-Z, approximately 1930-1995; [RESTRICTED] (Box 46)
  - "Coeducation: A Special Report on Admission,", 1974 Oct 7 (Folder 36.53)
  - Eugenie Havemeyer's papers related to Yale/Vassar, 1967 (Folder 36.54)
  - Frances D. Fergusson Farewell Dinner Photographs, 2006; (compact disc) (Folder 36.55)
  - Harriet Taylor Mauk, 1950-1951 (Folder 36.56)
  - Investments - South Africa, 1978 (Folder 36.57)
  - Meeting Agendas, 1964-1965 (Folder 36.58)
  - Nelson Report, 1975 (Folder 36.59)
  - Notices of Executive Committee Meetings, 1903-1919 (Folder 36.60)
  - Miscellaneous, 1973 (Folder 36.61)
  - Miscellaneous, 1977 (Folder 36.62)
  - "Resolutions made upon the death of Matthew Vassar,", 1868 Jun 26 (Box 53)